<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>General on Dictum mortuum&#39;s handbooks</title><link>https://dictummortuum.com/general/</link><description>Recent content in General on Dictum mortuum&#39;s handbooks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://dictummortuum.com/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>color codes</title><link>https://dictummortuum.com/general/colorcodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/general/colorcodes/</guid><description>color codes In the following guide I will be using the color coding that I introduced during the days of 3.5e in the wizards&amp;rsquo; of the coast optimization forum. Unfortunately that guide is now lost, because the forum is defunct, but a forum poster named Clockwerk66 has posted it here. Normally, I prefer three colors and a fourth one that&amp;rsquo;s there to denote the best choices.
navy: this is a no-brainer.</description></item><item><title>rpg aphorisms</title><link>https://dictummortuum.com/general/aphorisms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/general/aphorisms/</guid><description>rpg aphorisms by Dimitris Raviolos
Index Advice for dungeon masters Advice for players Definitions For Dungeon Masters For any conclusion you want the PCs to make, include at least three clues Name your NPCs Throw obstacles at your PCs Appeal to all five of the senses Your stories should have a beginning, a middle and an end Avoid breaking suspension of disbelief Build a cast of ready made NPCs Reuse NPCs when possible Keep your players motivated Thou shalt not afflict players with thine own awe-inspiring characters Thou shalt not place thy plot above player wishes Thou shalt not display preferential treatment The seven basic plots &amp;hellip; plus two!</description></item><item><title>rpg mechanics</title><link>https://dictummortuum.com/general/mechanics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/general/mechanics/</guid><description>RPG mechanics by Dimitris Raviolos
Index buy-in buy-in keep your character involved in the story
The &amp;ldquo;buy-in&amp;rdquo; rule from Feng Shui 2 makes the player responsible of keeping his character involved in a story, instead of the game master.
If the game master says &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a fire over at the museum&amp;rdquo;, the players need to figure out a reason that their character would want to check that out and get involved.</description></item></channel></rss>