<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>A random title on Dictum mortuum&#39;s handbooks</title><link>https://dictummortuum.com/</link><description>Recent content in A random title on Dictum mortuum&#39;s handbooks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://dictummortuum.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/assamite/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/assamite/</guid><description> danse in the dark assamite The righteous chosen of a blood cult, the Assassins are masters of silent death and an arcane tradition of wisdom.
attributes 1 prowl 2 skirmish special abilities silence of the blood path of blood xp you struggled with your bloodlust for cainite blood</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/brujah/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/brujah/</guid><description> danse in the dark brujah Hotheaded rebel warrior-philosophers, the rabble chafe at the shackles of tyranny while dreaming of their destroyed utopia
attributes 1 study 2 skirmish mortal background gang member graffiti artist hacker philosophy major radical activist slam poet urban homesteader xp you struggled with fallout from your great passions or your berserker rage</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/gangrel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/gangrel/</guid><description> danse in the dark gangrel Loners and wanderers comfortable away from the city, the bestial outlanders avoid getting embroiled in kindred politics
attributes 2 hunt 1 wreck mortal background drifter homesteader mechanic motorcycle gang member park ranger travel writer truck driver xp you struggle with fallout from your bestial instincts or your animal nature</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/giovanni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/giovanni/</guid><description> danse in the dark giovanni attributes 1 command 2 attune xp you struggled by the excruciating pain your Kiss causes.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/lasombra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/lasombra/</guid><description> danse in the dark lasombra attributes 2 command 1 survey xp</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/malkavian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/malkavian/</guid><description> danse in the dark malkavian The lunatics have uncanny insight and superhuman clarity of vision, but are forever touched with a hint of madness
attributes 2 survey 1 attune mortal background inmate art dealer conspiracy theorist fake psychic preacher psychologist soccer mom xp you struggle with fallout from your madness or uncanny insight</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/nosferatu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/nosferatu/</guid><description> danse in the dark nosferatu Hideous, disfigured monsters, the sewer rats lurk in dark places and collect dark secrets
attributes 2 prowl 1 study mortal background street person actor drug addict instagram model janitor nun sleazy lawyer xp you struggle with fallout from your hideous appearance</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/ravnos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/ravnos/</guid><description> danse in the dark ravnos attributes 1 finesse 2 sway xp</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/setites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/setites/</guid><description> danse in the dark followers of set attributes 1 prowl 2 sway xp you struggled with your extreme light sensitivity</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/toreador/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/toreador/</guid><description> danse in the dark toreador Lovers of art, the degenerates revel in sensation and debauchery to stave off the stagnant despair of undeath
attributes 1 finesse 2 consort mortal background art collector gadfly musician painter playwright poet sculptor xp you struggled with fallout from your obsession with art and intense sensory experiences</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/tremere/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/tremere/</guid><description> danse in the dark tremere The secretive warlocks, masters of blood sorcery, are both distrusted and feared by other kindred
attributes 1 study 2 attune mortal background librarian bookstore owner dilettante medical examiner novelist occult dabbler obsessive journalist xp you struggle with fallout from your addiction to the blood of kindred</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/tzimisce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/tzimisce/</guid><description> danse in the dark Tzimisce attributes 2 finesse 1 survey xp</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/ventrue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/ditd/playbooks/ventrue/</guid><description> danse in the dark ventrue The blue bloods are the aristocracy of the undead and enforcers of tradition, firm in their belief that it is their right to rule
attributes 2 command 1 consort mortal background junior executive gang leader litigator made man military officer political operative socialite xp you struggle with fallout from your rarified tastes or feeding restrictions</description></item><item><title>color codes</title><link>https://dictummortuum.com/general/colorcodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/general/colorcodes/</guid><description>color codes In the following guide I will be using the color coding that I introduced during the days of 3.5e in the wizards&amp;rsquo; of the coast optimization forum. Unfortunately that guide is now lost, because the forum is defunct, but a forum poster named Clockwerk66 has posted it here. Normally, I prefer three colors and a fourth one that&amp;rsquo;s there to denote the best choices.
navy: this is a no-brainer.</description></item><item><title>hexblade</title><link>https://dictummortuum.com/dnd35/hexblade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/dnd35/hexblade/</guid><description>the hexblade&amp;rsquo;s handbook by Dimitris Raviolos
Introduction why hexblade? Hexblades are fighters with a touch of arcane magic. As such they need high physical stats to be able to get through a fight and nice charisma to get the maximum of their abilities. Be warned that playing a hexblade in a competent campaign can prove to be quite a challenge. While they are proved to be better than most martial classes in the player&amp;rsquo;s handbook due to their magic abilities, their skills are quite limited.</description></item><item><title>rpg aphorisms</title><link>https://dictummortuum.com/general/aphorisms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dictummortuum.com/general/aphorisms/</guid><description>rpg aphorisms Index Advice for dungeon masters Advice for players Definitions For Dungeon Masters For any conclusion you want the PCs to make, include at least three clues Name your NPCs Throw obstacles at your PCs Appeal to all five of the senses Your stories should have a beginning, a middle and an end Avoid breaking suspension of disbelief Build a cast of ready made NPCs Reuse NPCs when possible Keep your players motivated Thou shalt not afflict players with thine own awe-inspiring characters Thou shalt not place thy plot above player wishes Thou shalt not display preferential treatment The seven basic plots &amp;hellip; plus two!</description></item></channel></rss>